糟糕
Oh, no.
又過去一年了嗎
Has it been a year already?
? 你是一面偉大古老的旗幟 ?
♪ You're a grand old flag ♪
? 一面高揚的旗幟 ?
♪ You're a high-flying flag ♪
? 愿你永遠飄揚在和平年代 ?
♪ And forever in peace may you wave ♪
我們熱愛國慶節
We love the Fourth of July.
這個節日太完美了
It's the perfect holiday.
你可以在戶外烹飪 放煙花 穿短褲
You get to cook outside, blow stuff up, wear shorts.
復活節該好好學學
Easter should be taking notes.
? 好好望著這偉大古老的旗幟 ?
♪ Keep your eyes on the grand old flag ♪
比我記憶中的還漫長
That was longer than I remember.
你好
Hello?
喬 你該感恩你生活在這個國家
Joe, you should be thankful that you live in this country.
我的半個童年都在服飾店香蕉共和國度過
I spent half of my childhood in a Banana Republic.
那是我們村里唯一有空調的商店
It was the only store in my village that had air-conditioner.
遵命 主席先生
Yes, Mr. President.
遵命 這是我的榮幸 謝謝您
Yes, sir, I'd be honored to, sir. Thank you.
天大的好消息
Amazing news.
今天游行的大禮官爆出性侵丑聞了
The grand marshal for today's parade just got #MeToo'd,
他們叫我去接任
and they need me to fill in.
杰 我真替你高興
Oh, Jay, I'm so happy for you!
現在你遺愿清單上沒實現的
So, now the only thing left on your bucket list
只有赤手空拳大戰俄國佬了
is to bare-knuckle fight a Russian!
曼尼的公路大旅行就快結束了
Oh, and Manny's gonna be back home
他能及時趕回家看游行
from his big road trip just in time for the parade.
他走了這么久 我等不及見他了
He's been gone for so long. I can't wait to see him.
太好了
That's great!
到時全家人都能齊聚 和我一起
We'll have the whole family back together with me
乘男爵敞篷車
to ride in the convertible LeBaron.
喬 你的游行揮手練得如何了
Joe, how's your parade wave?
我們再努力改進
We'll work on it.
? 在紅白藍的旗幟下 ?
♪ Every heart beats true ♪
? 每顆心臟都真摯地跳動著 ?
♪ For the red, white, and blue ♪
? 將永遠沒有... ?
♪ Where there's never a... ♪
還要
More!
行 我有時間幫你
Yeah. I've got time to help you.
看你表姐人多好 幫朋友的忙
Oh, look at your cousin being so sweet and helping out a friend.
你這個軟弱的小懦夫
Such a weak little coward.
還沒搞定嗎
Are we done yet?
沒有 這座橋真的很大
No. It's a really big bridge.
或許是你這個人真的很渺小
Or maybe you're just a really tiny man.
我的橫跨美國公路旅行很順利
Things were going great on my cross-country drive
直到我突然患上了
until I fell behind schedule
完全合理 基于事實的過橋恐懼癥
after I developed a perfectly rational, fact-based fear
進度就耽誤了
of driving over bridges.
我打電話找小卡幫忙
I called Cam for support
因為他做過駕駛教練
since he taught driver's ed,
但他不在
but he wasn't around.
干嘛啦
What?
原來嚴厲的言語痛斥
Turns out a strong verbal lashing
正好能激勵我過那座橋
was exactly what I needed to get me across that bridge
還有像癌癥一樣遍布全國的所有橋
and the many others that cover this country like a cancer.
好了 卡爾 來和媽媽打個招呼
Okay, Cal. Let's say hi to Mommy.
說"媽媽 你好"
Say, "Hi, Mommy!"
要是我入鏡了 后退一點再把燈關上
If I'm in that shot, back up a-and turn the lights down.
咱昨晚吃的是中餐 我人都水腫了
We had Chinese food last night. I look like a blowfish.
知道嗎 米奇爾 你不是重點
Okay, you know what, Mitchell? It's not about you.
我向我姐保證過 會在她過生日時
I promised we would send a video of Cal
給她發卡爾的視頻
to my sister for her birthday,
已經過去一周了 我們必須把視頻拍好
and that was a week ago, so we got to get it done.
我們一直在照看
We have been watching
個頭看起來比年齡大的外甥卡爾
my big-for-his-age nephew Cal
我姐姐帕梅隆
while my sister Pameron is --
回密蘇里去償還一些債務
is back in Missouri paying off a little debt.
還社會的債 她進監獄了
To society. She's in prison.
因為稍微違反了假釋條例
For a tiny parole violation.
她在某間商店試穿商品
She tried something on in a store
不小心就那么走出了商店
and accidentally walked out.
她帶走的是另一個女人的包
It was another woman's purse.
不幸中的一線希望是
The silver lining is,
卡爾因為我們的育兒經驗十分受益
Cal is benefiting from our parenting experience.
米奇爾在讓卡爾的小腦袋瓜成型
Mitchell is molding young Cal's brain
我則負責撫弄孩子的身體
while I handle the young boy's body.
我們沒坐牢真是奇跡
It's a miracle we're not in prison.
是啊
Yeah.
好 我們為媽媽唱字母歌吧
Okay, let's sing the alphabet for Mommy.
快來 我們練過的
Come on, you and I worked on this.
A B
A B.
Six.
我想是我傳授的信息太多了
You know, I think I put so much information in there,
他說話時就搞混了
it's getting jumbled up on the way out.
我們拍點你教的東西
Well, let's-let's do some of your stuff.
丟個球給他接之類的
Throw him a ball or something.
好 這主意好
Oh, okay, yeah. That's a great idea.
好了 我數到三 卡爾
Okay, on the count of 3, Cal.
準備好了嗎 1 2 3
Are you ready? 1, 2, 3!
好吧
Oh. Okay.
那好吧 擁抱
All right, um... well, hugs!
來擁抱一下好嗎
Hey, how about a hug?
他真擅長擁抱
He is such a good hugger.
好吧 是這樣的
Okay, here's the thing --
卡爾來咱家時橄欖球集訓營開始了
football camp started when Cal came.
之后我因為
Then I was laid up
那頓螃蟹大餐臥床不起
because of that dinner at Absolutely Crabulous.
別擔心 我這邊做得也不好
Well, don't worry. I've been slacking on my end, too.
是的 可我一直對小帕說
Yeah, but I've been telling Pam
卡爾在這成長得特別好
that Cal is thriving here.
我們不能把他背AB6的視頻發過去
We can't send her a video of him reciting his AB6s!
我在想
I wonder...
接著說 我入伙
Go on. I'm in.
有沒有可能用拍攝技巧
Is it possible to shoot him in a way
讓他看起來比實際做得好
that makes him look better than he is?
這還用問嗎 范·迪塞爾都能當影星
Oh, honey, are you kidding? Vin Diesel's a movie star.
剪輯能使一切成為可能
Anything's possible with editing.
你拿的是什么
What do you got there?
我只是在選大學課程
Oh, just choosing some classes for college.
這個看起來挺有趣的
This one looks interesting.
"本加強課程..."
"In this intensive" --
算了
Nope.
快放下
Drop that!
今天是比賽日 伙計
Game day, buddy.
有史以來第一次 盧克和我
For the first time ever, Luke and I
要參加體育項目之王
are taking part in the sport of kings,
最美味的科學
the savory science.
我們組隊參加了親子熱狗大胃王比賽
We're teamed in a parent/child hot-dog-eating contest.
我們已經訓練了幾周 我非常驕傲地說
We've been training for weeks, and I'm proud to say that Luke,
盧克和他爹一樣 天生一張吃熱狗的嘴
like his old man, is blessed with a dogger's mouth.
我覺得肚子里某個地方裂開了
I felt something tear inside.
挺過去
Push through it.
撐到爽以后你會感謝我的
You'll thank me when you start to feel the gorger's high.
搞什么
What the hell?!
熱狗讓你生氣了嗎
Oh, is the hot dog making you angry?
人生氣時胃會變大12%
An angry stomach is 12% larger.
我覺得我們有很大機會
I think we've got a real shot
能戰勝朗達和譚蒂·霍達克家
to take down Rhonda and Thandie Hodak.
可她們從沒輸過
But they're undefeated.
看來我們是"落水熱狗"
I guess that makes us "Under-dogs."
你這個哏憋了多久了
How long you been sitting on that one?
沒你在那個沙發上坐得久
Not as long as you've been sitting on that couch.
你地上撿的百吉餅分我一半好嗎
Hey, hey. Can I get in on that floor bagel?
艾麗克斯今年暑假開始時決定放松一下
Alex decided to take off some time earlier this summer,
就像她做的所有事一樣
and, like everything else she does,
她有點擅長過頭了
she did it a little too well.
是誰
Who's there?
你拿吃的來了嗎
Did you bring food?
番茄
Uh...tomatoes.
不過還要六周才能吃
But they won't be ready for six weeks.
你居然還有備用的
You have a backup?
我壓在手機上睡著了
Well, I fell asleep on my phone,
好像是我的臉又訂購了一件
and I think my face ordered another one.
你想和我一起放松嗎
You know, do you want to join me?
幾周后你就要回去工作了
You go back to work in a few weeks.
不放松一下你會后悔的
You'll regret it if you don't relax a little.
好吧 當然好
Uh, okay. Sure.
這個等十分鐘再種到地里也行 對嗎
The-this can wait 10 minutes until I get him into the ground, right?
幫我撓撓鼻子好嗎 我覺得你的手更近
Can you scratch my nose? I feel like you're closer.
躺桌子上做肚子按摩
Okay, up on the table for a little stomach massage
和面對喝倒彩的心理準備
and heckler prep.
美女們 我和阿爾文最近不太順利
Hey, gals, things haven't been going that great
他等會來道別完
between me and Arvin, and he's stopping by
就要去瑞士了
to say goodbye before leaving for Switzerland.
你們能不能脫掉一件式連身睡衣
Could you take off the onesies
別搞得像我們住在瘋人院一樣
and make it look like we don't live in an insane asylum?
你弱爆了 你吃相真蠢
You suck! You eat like a moron!
老天啊
Oh, my God!
你們簡直是要逼阿爾文
It's like you want Arvin
把回程機票從一座阿爾卑丟下來
to throw his return ticket off an Alp!
難怪她情緒這么緊繃
Mm. No wonder she's so stressed.
她穿了大概有7件式吧
She's wearing, like, a seven-sie.
海莉 在這遇見你好巧啊
Haley. Fancy meeting you here.
為什么 我住在這兒啊
Wait, why? I-I live here.
我知道 我只是想幽默一把
No, I-I know. I was -- I was making a joke.
好傻
It was stupid.
不傻 很好笑
Oh, no, it -- it wasn't stupid. It was funny.
但你沒笑
Well, you didn't laugh.
再說一遍 這次我會笑的
Well, do it again. I'll laugh this time.
還是算了吧
I'd rather not.
對不起 我只是有點
Sorry. I'm just, um, a little --
我很緊張 我覺得這次分別
I'm really nervous, and I feel like this goodbye
壓力很大
has so much pressure on it.
我們就放輕松 好好相處吧
So let's just relax and be with each other.
其實我現在就得走了
I actually have to go.
我是說真的
No, seriously.
我看錯行程表了
I misread my itinerary,
現在就得趕去機場
and I have to get to the airport.
不要啊 就這樣了嗎
No! So, uh, this is it?
這就是道別了
This is goodbye?
恐怕是的
I'm afraid so.
我會想你的
I'm gonna miss you.
我也會想你的
I'll miss you, too.
那是我的車 我該...
That's my car. I should probably --
好吧 再見了 海莉
Okay. Uh, well... goodbye, Haley.
愛你哦
Love you.
我也愛你
Love you, too.
他走了嗎
Is he gone?
-對 -太好了
- Yeah? - Oh, good.
沒人想被話嘮老爹
No one wants old fuddy-duddy dad
毀掉浪漫時刻
ruining the big romantic moment.
我去樓上躲進盧克的衣柜里
I'll be upstairs hiding in Luke's closet.
好了 來 卡爾 嚼花生醬
All right. There we go, Cal. Chew the peanut butter.
看見沒 現在經過剪輯后
See? Now, with editing,
我們想讓他看起來在說什么都行
we can make it look like he's saying anything we want --
數字 字母表 開猶太人玩笑
numbers, the alphabet, a joke about Jewish people.
小帕可喜歡了
Pam loves those.
電影拍攝技巧對我不是難事
Movie tricks come easy to me --
畢竟小丑就是很會騙人的
you know, clowns being naturals at deception.
沒錯 我們當初約會了幾個月后
It's true -- a couple months into dating,
小卡告訴我他是一名小丑
Cam told me he was a clown,
還表演給我看
did a little performance for me,
而我的確感到上當受騙了
and I -- I did feel deceived.
好了 我說"開拍"時
Okay, now, when I say "Action,"
卡爾就把球丟給我
Cal's gonna throw me the ball.
你就倒著走
You're gonna walk backwards,
然后我重新剪輯 倒放
and then in editing, I'll reverse it
看起來就會像卡爾接住了球
to make it look like Cal's catching the ball
而你在正常往前走
and you're walking normally.
為什么要把我拍進去
Why am I even in it at all?
米奇爾 提醒我一下 最偉大的藝術作品
Remind me of something, Mitchell -- is the best art made
是很多人七嘴八舌還是一個人獨立創作出來的
by a million voices chiming in or one man with a single vision?
等會再剪輯琴音進去
Okay, and we'll lay in the piano later.
? 一閃一閃亮晶晶 ?
♪ Twinkle, twinkle, little star ♪
? 滿天都是小星星 ?
♪ How I wonder what you are ♪
-我要尿尿 -他要尿尿
- I have to pee! - He has to pee.
-好 他要尿尿 -對
- Okay, he has to pee. - Yep.
休息五分鐘
All right. Take five!
莉莉 這是初剪
Lily, this is our first cut,
如果發現穿幫畫面就告訴我們
so if you see anything wonky, let us know.
媽咪你好呀
Oh. Hello, Mommy.
生日快樂
Happy birthday.
一加一等于二
1 plus 1 is 2.
很簡單的數學題
Simple math.
我能接住球
I can catch a ball.
你怎么沒看到貓經過
How'd you miss the cat?
我看見了 那條剪輯是你最自然的一次了
I didn't. That take was your best walk.
這畫面太贊了
That is gold.
為什么旁邊要放這么大的酒瓶
Why the giant bottle of wine?
這樣顯得腳小
It's for perspective,
沒人會問這個問題
and nobody's asking that question.
我剛不是問了嗎
Didn't I just ask it?
小卡
Cam.
我知道 已被權威認證爛透了
Yeah, I know. It's certified rotten.
盧克
Luke.
他第一口只咬進1/3根香腸
He's only getting 1/3 of the dog on his first bite.
至少得咬半根 否則就跟冠軍無緣了
Anything less than half, and you're playing for second.
好消息是離國慶節還有幾周呢
Well, the good news is, the Fourth is weeks away.
今天就是國慶
It's -- it's today.
今天
Toda--
六月呢
June...?
已經過了
Yeah -- gone.
你在這兒呢 我們的節目快開始了
There you are! It's almost time for our show.
等等 你穿的是什么
Wait -- what are you wearing?
衣服
Clothes?
我得重拾上學狀態
I got to get back into school mode
不然我的犀利就沒了
before I lose my edge.
媽媽 你最好考慮一下重返人間
Mom, you might want to think about rejoining life
不然你的腦子也要廢了
before your brain freezes, too.
你才不用擔心...
Yeah, don't you worry about...
我
Me.
那是什么聲音
What's that?
聽我說
Listen.
沒有一個父親想和兒子談論這個話題
No dad wants to have this talk with his son, but...
但你吃的熱狗不夠多
you're just not eating enough hot dogs.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
不知為什么 我就是沒法集中精神
For some reason, I just -- I can't focus.
我想盧克想說的是
I think what Luke is trying to say is,
他早過了參加這種比賽的年紀
he's too old for this contest
但他不忍心告訴你
and he doesn't have the heart to tell you.
不可能 我是大人了 我還是對比賽充滿激情
That's impossible. I'm an adult. I'm still super into it.
是啊 二十幾歲應該是我吃熱狗的鼎盛時期
Yeah. My 20s should be my prime hot-dog-eating years.
剛才是我第一個猜測
That was just my first attempt.
我會想明白的 等等
I'm gonna figure this out. Hang on.
不管艾麗克斯怎么說 我還是一如既往地犀利
Despite what Alex says, I have not lost my edge.
感覺有怪啊
Something just clicked.
好吧 你說得對 是大學的事
Fine. You're right -- it's college.
-真的嗎 -對
- It is? - Yeah.
我分心是因為我壓力很大
I'm distracted because I'm feeling some pressure
不知道該選哪門課
on which classes to take.
不過別擔心 我會想好的
But don't worry. I'm gonna figure it out.
你怎么看出來的
Wow. How could you tell?
我只是 觀察力很敏銳
I'm just a... perceptive guy.
我當時不是在說盧克 是我下巴發出怪響了
I wasn't talking about Luke. The clicking was in my jaw.
由于密集訓練 我顳下頜關節的舊傷復發
My old TMJ injury was back, thanks to all the training.
這個傷是我念大學時 和室友打賭
I got it in college when I bet my roommate
我比他的金毛獵犬接飛盤還厲害而得來的
I could out-Frisbee-catch his golden retriever.
猜猜誰贏...
And guess who wo-- Aah!
阿爾文和我的告別糟透了
Arvin and I had the worst goodbye.
過去幾個月好怪
Aww. It's been such a weird past couple months.
這么久了嗎
That long?
好像是從在醫院
It feels like it all started in the hospital,
我告訴他我愛他之后開始的
after I told him I loved him.
找到原因了
There you go.
就是這個 你給他壓力了
That's it. You pressured him.
-太投入 太快了 -或許吧
- Too much, too soon. - Maybe.
好像有哪里對不上啊
Something's not lining up.
好吧 你說得對
Okay, you're right.
又被你看透啦
Seriously?!
阿爾文不在病房時
Something happened in the hospital
發生了一件事
while Arvin was gone.
又迷路了
Lost again?
不 這次我是特意回來的
No. This time, I meant to come back.
我有一件大事想告訴你
I have some pretty big news.
你最好是坐著聽
You should probably be sitting for this.
好吧
O...kay.
我說謊了
I lied.
我已經離婚了
I'm not married anymore.
我妻子跑回她前夫的身邊了
My wife left me for her ex-husband.
我現在是離婚之人
I'm a divorce.
你為什么要告訴我這個
Why are you telling me this?
因為我搬回來這里了 我要上護理學校
Because I'm back in town, I'm going to nursing school,
我們可能會在路上碰到
and we might run into each other.
我不想接下來這一輩子
I don't want to spend the rest of my life
都在假裝我妻子剛好去廁所了
pretending my wife is in the bathroom.
的確 幾次之后我就會開始擔心她有膀胱問題了
Yeah, I would start to worry about her after a while.
很遺憾你的婚姻沒能走下去
Well, I'm sorry it didn't work out.
沒事 我也一直覺得我跟她沒心靈相通過
It's okay. I don't think we ever really got each other.
比如你還記得我們以前一起去看演唱會時
Like, you know how when you and I used to go to concerts,
我們有過就這么看著彼此就知道...
we used to just look at each other and know...
是讓我坐到你肩膀上
It was time for me to get on your shoulders
我把胸罩丟給鼓手的時刻到了
and throw my bra at the drummer.
是啊
Yeah.
你跟阿爾文也有這樣的默契對吧
Like, you probably have that with Arvin, right?
-絕對的 -那太棒了
- Definitely. - That's awesome.
至于我的妻子呢
With my wife,
她漂亮又聰明 還是個醫生
she's pretty and smart and a doctor.
但如果你總是在告訴自己
But if you're always telling yourself
找到對方真是撞大運了
how lucky you are,
那很可能是因為你害怕捫心自問
it's probably because you're afraid to ask yourself
自己到底開不開心
how happy you are.
對吧
Right?
我給你拿碎冰塊過來啦
I brought ice chips.
還是你們美國叫碎冰薯條呢
Or are they ice fries here?
呵
Ha.
我真不敢相信被迪蘭亂了心
I can't believe Dylan got into my head.
我不敢相信他居然能考進護理學校
I can't believe he got into nursing school.
它們最大把就只有這么大嗎
That's the biggest one they got?
是的 我也不想再回去一趟了
Yes, and I'm not going back again.
你有看到曼尼嗎 我在到處找他呢
Have you seen Manny? I've been looking all over for him.
都沒找到他
I don't see him.
我一直在這忙著巡視軍樂隊
I've been here, busy inspecting the troops.
女孩 你能把帽子戴好嗎
Young lady, could you straighten that hat?
先生 你的號可以去擦亮點
Sir, that -- that horn could use a shine.
去剪頭發
Haircut.
歌洛莉亞 如果今天順利 幾個月之后
Gloria, if this goes well, in a couple of months,
本地的圣誕樹就會由我負責點亮啦
I'll be lighting the town Christmas tree.
認輸吧 老爸
Take that, Dad!
你知道哪里很奇怪嗎
You know what is weird?
去過我們南美那么多年的狂歡節
After so many years at Carnivale,
你們這里的人衣服穿那么嚴實 太怪了
to be at a parade with people fully dressed.
歌洛莉亞 集中點
Gloria, focus.
你的職責很重大呢
You've got a big role in this.
當我剪斷緞帶后
After I cut the ribbon,
你得負責發射大炮
it's your job to fire off the cannon.
那是讓大家開始游行的信號
That's the signal for everybody to start marching.
但難道不是由游行大禮官來發射大炮嗎
But isn't the grand marshal's job to fire the cannon?
這緞帶會自己剪斷自己嗎
So the ribbon cuts itself?
歌洛莉亞 你不懂游行的地方是...
Gloria, what you don't know about parades...
等等 稍等
Wait, wait.
寶貝
Papi! Hello.
你還來嗎 游行都要開始了
Are you coming? The parade is about to start.
杰
Hey! Jay!
湯姆 你好嗎
Hey, Tom! How's it going?
其實最近很好呢
Great, actually.
我跟我太太重修舊好了
My wife and I, we're back together.
其實也還沒到完整如初
I-- Well, not exactly.
但我們又重新開始約會
I mean, we're going on dates.
-我們希望能重拾... -行行行
- We're hoping to recapture... - Yeah, yeah.
我十分想聽你們的事情
I want to hear all about it,
但本地的報社想找我拍照
but I think the local paper needs a photo.
當然啦 沒問題
Oh. O-Of course. Yeah.
歌洛莉亞 來合影
Gloria, get in the shot.
歌洛莉亞
Gloria.
但你答應過你會來的
But you promised that you were going to come.
你就拍吧 沒事 直接拍[發射]吧
Just shoot. No, go ahead -- shoot it.
什么 行吧
What? Okay.
別別 還沒呢
No, no, not yet!
靠 歌洛莉亞 剪不斷啊
Damn it, Gloria! It's not cutting!
這不是左撇子用的剪刀
These aren't lefties!
游行大禮官
Grand Marshal.
認輸吧 爺爺
Take that, Grandpa!
你肯定感覺自己是世界之王了
You must be on top of the world.
我現在是故作鎮定
Well, I'm putting on a brave face
為了不給國家添亂 但事實上呢
for the good of the country, but the truth is,
我們這開頭并不順利
we did not get off to a great start.
歌洛莉亞今天狀態不佳
Gloria is not on her game today,
我很擔心她會忘記
and I'm afraid she's gonna forget
自己得負責在我演講完帶領群眾起身鼓掌
to lead the standing ovation after my speech.
其實呢 我想要委任于你
Hm. In fact, I'm tagging you in.
當你聽到"追逐幸福"就是信號
Your cue is "Pursuit of happiness."
如果演技夠好 吼一句"太棒了"也無妨
And if you could sell it, a "bravo" Would be nice.
行了 我知道歌洛莉亞是出了什么問題
Okay. I-I know what's wrong with Gloria.
今天是你的大日子 而她感覺被冷落了
This is a big day for you, and she's feeling left out.
不 才不是這樣
No, that's not it.
靠
Damn it.
你要到明天才能到嗎
You're not getting here till tomorrow?
你名字里的尼改成"妮"才對吧
How does your name even have the word "man" in it?
我恍然大悟了[有怪響]
Something just clicked.
-下巴有問題嗎 -不是
- Jaw trouble? - No!
她是在煩曼尼的事 他來不了嘛
She was just on with Manny, who's not coming.
歌洛莉亞跟曼尼不是有些國慶節傳統嗎
Don't Gloria and Manny have some Fourth of July tradition?
經你這么一說
Come to think of it,
他們會一起分食蘋果派 再一同看煙花
they share a slice of apple pie and watch the fireworks.
從他出生那年就開始了這個傳統
They've been doing that every year since he was born!
直到今年沒戲了 所以歌洛莉亞不開心
Until this year, which is why Gloria is upset.
-中啦 -你說得對
- Yes! - You're right!
我讓游行的肩帶沖昏了頭
Mm-hmm. I let the sash go to my head.
我壓根就不該帶來
I never should have brought it!
我能幫到你
Oh, I can help you out,
但你可能得放棄掉演講的這件事了
but you're gonna have to give up on your little speech thing.
孩子 你等等 你去哪弄來的煙花
Hey, kid. Whoa, whoa, whoa. Where'd you get the fireworks?
你是條子嗎
You a cop?
你開玩...
Oh, co--
在超市停車場有個小攤
There's a stand in the grocery store parking lot.
不過他要收工了
But he's closing up.
你去買煙花跟蘋果派
You get the fireworks and the apple pie.
我來負責搞定曼尼
I will take care of Manny.
我回來啦 犀利姐王者歸來
I am back. I am really back!
我的車被堵起來了
My car's blocked in.
這么多車流人群 我到不了的
All this traffic, I'll never make it.
看到沒 就在那里
Look at that -- right there.
快看 我是施里納
Check out! I'm a Shriner.
贊啊 聽我說 我想借用你的車子
Cool! Listen, I need to borrow your car.
有很緊急的事情
It's kind of an emergency.
但我爸爸很期待看到我出現在游行里呢
But my dad's excited to see me in the parade.
他曾是個塔斯克基飛行員呢
He was a Tuskegee Airman.
或許當你開始停止過度渴求他的愛時
Maybe the minute you stop trying so hard
他才會真正開始愛你
is the minute he'll start loving you.
現在快給我下車去為我在
Now hop out of there and go clear a path for me
草地的椅子陣中開路
through those lawn chairs.
-快點 我拉你一把 -但是我不...
- Come on. I'll help you out. - But...I don't --
玩玩這個怎么樣
Oh, how about this one, okay?
或許我們運氣好能選到他的強項
Maybe we'll get lucky and he'll be good at this.
你不覺得這游戲太充滿憎恨嗎
Okay, don't you think this is a little hateful --
-水刑一個小丑來得獎品 -少來了
- waterboarding a clown for a prize? - Oh, come on.
你們整天互相用氣泡水噴對方
You guys spray each other with seltzer all the time.
那是在彼此同意的小丑之間玩的游戲
That's between two consenting clowns.
好啦 等我一下 準備開拍
All right, one second. Let's get this.
好 你開始吧
Okay, go ahead. Okay.
不 不對 反了 拿反了
No. No. Wrong way, wrong way.
你得... 你得朝...
Oh, okay, all right, all right, You got to --
-算了 沒事 -其實呢
- Okay, it's fine. - You know what?
或許我們是時候跟小帕坦白
Maybe it's just time we admit to Pam
我們什么都沒教會他
we haven't taught him a thing.
其實我... 我只是不想對他做得不好
You know, I just -- I don't want to let him down.
我開始習慣并喜歡有他的陪伴了
I-I've come to really enjoy having him around.
我懂 我也是
I know, I know. Me too.
但這并不是因為我們不會教孩子啊
But it's not like we're bad at parenting.
你看莉莉就長成了一個聰明善解人意的姑娘
I mean, Lily turned out to be a smart, sensitive little girl.
你太給我們這個家族丟臉了
Ugh! You're a disgrace to this family!
你是不是沒聽清楚我說的 我開過橋了啊
I don't think you heard me. I'm over the bridge.
我知道啊 我們只是在敘敘舊而已
I know. Now we're just catching up.
對不起 我沒有贏
Sorry I didn't win.
沒事沒事 你不用道歉 知道嗎
Oh, no, no, no. You don't have to apologize, okay?
沒事的 你做得很棒了
No, no, you did just great.
我們才是應該要做得更好的人
Oh! We're the ones who need to do better.
而且其實啊 你很會抱抱呢
And you know what? You give great hugs.
這是我們教會他的
Hey. We taught him that.
可惜這算不上什么技能
Well, too bad it isn't exactly a skill.
是嗎
Or is it?
羊國英雄
Mutton busting?!
什么 那是什么玩意
Why? What is that?
是兒童版的騎羊大賽
It's a sheep rodeo for kids.
感覺你壓根就沒有童年啊
It's like you didn't even have a childhood.
來吧
Come on!
熱狗大胃王比賽馬上要開始啦
The hot dog contest is about to begin.
抱歉我的戰斗狀態不夠好
Sorry I'm not in worse shape for this.
沒事的孩子 你心里很多煩心事嘛
Don't worry about it, buddy. You've had a lot on your mind.
選課的事情有眉目了嗎
Any luck choosing your courses?
還沒
Not yet.
我現在不是很想談這件事
I don't really want to talk about that right now.
或許是你過度給自己壓力...
Maybe you're putting too much pressure on --
這不只是單純的選課好嗎
It's more than just picking classes, okay?
能不談那件事 專心眼前的比賽嗎
Can we just drop it and focus on what we're doing here?
當然啦 沒問題
Yeah. Of course.
參加比賽很興奮吧
Exciting to be in the competition, huh?
比過去三年在觀眾席旁觀強太多了
Instead of sitting up in the bleachers, like the last three years?
應該是吧
I guess.
令人恐慌 但那一種
Scary, sure, but it does feel good
下場爭取勝利的感覺也很爽
putting our butts on the line.
你輸掉沒參加的熱狗比賽的幾率是100%
You lose 100% of the hot-dog-eating contests you don't enter.
爸 我知道你的汽車貼紙寫了什么
Dad, I know what your bumper sticker is,
我也聽出了你話中有話的招數
and I know what you're trying to do here.
但上大學不一樣啊
But college is different.
當你連社區大學都沒讀好時 你就真走投無路了
I mean, you screw up at community college, you're out of options.
你不會沒讀好的
You're not gonna screw it up.
我這一生沒做好的事情太多了
I've messed up a lot of things in my life.
我很害怕會又重蹈覆轍
I'm scared I'll do it again.
-很好啊 -什么
- Good. - What?
你在乎了才會害怕
Being scared means you care.
或許... 或許你以前就是少了這份在乎的心
Maybe -- Maybe that's what's been missing in the past.
這是我此生嘗試過最重大的事情了
It's the biggest thing I've ever tried to do.
參賽者們 各就各位
Contestants, ready position.
一步一步來
Just take it one step at a time.
別擔心接下來要吃掉的50份
Don't worry about the 50 to hopefully 75 hot dogs
或最好75份的熱狗
you're gonna eat.
你就專注眼前的那一份就行了
Just worry about the dog in front of you.
還有別忘了沾濕面包
And wet the buns.
開吃
Eat!
-你確定這個安全嗎 -天啊 那當然
- Are we sure this is safe? - Oh, my gosh, yes.
這游戲小孩愛玩 羊也愛玩
The kids love it, the sheep love it.
而且我挺確定反悔也來不及了
And I'm pretty sure it's too late.
抱穩了 卡爾
Whoa! Hang on, Cal!
抱住別撒手
Keep hugging!
天啊 小帕看到一定超激動
Oh, my gosh. Pam is gonna be so excited.
卡爾的抱羊技術已經達到一年級生水平
He's already busting at a first-grade level.
最好去照個X光 你傷得挺重
Better get an X-ray. You got trampled pretty bad.
感覺你腳踝骨折了
Looks like that ankle's broken.
無不無聊啊 杰瑞
Really, Jerry?
海莉 你來這里干嘛
Haley? What are you doing here?
你發了推特說你在工作
Well, you tweeted you were working,
你在照片應用上的分享能看到你背后的水塔
the water tower's in the back of your Instagram story,
然后你還在點評應用上
and you just left a Yelp rating
給角落的那家炸丸子留評價了
for that falafel place around the corner,
所以我推理出你在哪里
so I figured out where you were.
你能不能不要再對我癡心糾纏
Could you please stop being so obsessed with me?
等... 你說什么
Wait -- what?
你在醫院里說的那一番話
That thing that you said at the hospital?
說如果覺得在一段感情中自己是賺到了
How if a person felt lucky to be in a relationship,
那這個人永遠不會真正開心
that means that they couldn't really be happy?
你說這番話很明顯是想毀了我跟阿爾文
Obviously, you did that to try and ruin what I have with Arvin,
因為你還沒放下我
because you're not over me.
我真的不知道我是該笑
I seriously don't know whether to laugh
還是該檢查你是不是被蜘蛛咬了
or check you for a spider bite.
你開始質疑自己的感情我很遺憾
I'm sorry that you're questioning your relationship,
但這不是我的錯啊
but it's not my fault.
你就老實承認吧
Just admit it!
你說那些話就是想跟我重修舊好
You said that to try and get back with me.
聽我說 在我內心的內心中
Look, in my heart of hearts --
雖然那地方并不存在
which does not exist, by the way --
是的 我還是有想著我們那段情
yeah, I still think about us.
我們很合
We were great.
-抓到了 -抓個屁
- Ah ha! - Not ha.
你才是那個大老遠開車過來
You're the one who drove across town,
還付了12塊停車費
paid $12 for parking
然后再額外花了2塊買了黃腕帶
and then an additional $2 for the yellow wristband
好得到啤酒與醫療照護服務
for beer and medical tent access.
感覺你才是對我戀戀不忘的人吧
It sounds like you're the one who's into me.
你神經病
You're crazy.
想著如果我們沒分手會如何
There's no crime in wondering
并沒有什么錯
if we might still be good together.
在我內心的雙眼中我還能看到我們在一起
I still see us together in my mind's eye --
-雖然那雙眼并不存在 -我不想再聽一次了
- which, by the way, doesn't exist. - I can't hear it again.
診斷結果 沒感情
Diagnosis -- nothing.
游行如何了
How was the parade?
我有更重要的事情要做
I had something more important to do.
蘋果派嗎
Apple pie?
我在駕駛購買窗口時被人用異樣眼光看了
I got a few weird looks at the drive-through,
但為了你們的節日傳統 那也值了
but it was worth it to help keep your tradition alive.
你是指我與曼尼嗎
You mean Manny and me?
這沒戲了 因為...
It's not gonna happen, because --
這部分我也搞定了
I've got that covered, too.
老媽 我很想你
Hi, Mom! I miss you!
杰 這真是太完美了
Oh, Jay! That's perfect!
還沒到完美呢
Oh, it's not perfect yet.
我們把這么危險的工作交給
Should we really give the dangerous job
我家唯一的聰明孩子合適嗎
to my only smart one?
國慶節快樂 寶貝
Happy Fourth of July, Papi!
我很快就會回家的 非常快
I'll be home soon -- before you know it.
"托馬斯·杰斐遜
"Thomas Jefferson,
他也算是他年代的游行大禮官之類的吧
who was sort of the grand marshal of his time,
他相信這個國家應該是個讓人民
believed this country should be a place where people are free
擁有自由追逐幸福與更好生活之地
to pursue happiness and a better life,
也是個可以展望無限星空與未來
where we can set our sights on the stars
而且只要努力并有決心
and, with hard work and determination...
就能夠讓一切不可能成真的地方"
...make the impossible a reality.
不是吧
No!
因為美國人從不在挑戰面前退卻
Because Americans don't run from challenges.
我們迎向挑戰
We embrace them.
天佑美國
God bless America.
然后等待掌聲"
Hold for applause."
這一席話絕對會震撼全場吧
That would've killed, right?
太棒了
Bravo!
我今天放棄了許多東西 你就不能走點心嗎
You know, I gave up a lot today. You could mean it.
為明年提前做訓練 再早都不嫌早
Never too early to start training for next year.
先做點暖身運動放松肌肉
Let's loosen up first from some exercises.
羊駝舔舌法
Lama lick.
小號手迪吉·葛拉斯彼法
Dizzy Gillespie
吐納法
Tiffy pop it.
憋住
Hold it.
吐出
And out.
爸 我覺得我這輩子再也吃不進熱狗了
Dad, I don't think I can ever eat another hot dog again.
我猜到了你可能會有這感覺
I thought you might feel this way.
你在嗎
Hey, you there?
干嘛啦
What?
我們碰到了困難 吃不下這些熱狗
We are having some troubles getting these bad boys down.
你們這兩廢柴我真是一點都不意外
I'm not surprised you pathetic losers.
你們倆比那些熱狗更讓我感到惡心
You two disgust me more than most of these hot dogs.
是哪里讓你們吃不下了
What's the hold up?
你們倆姑娘想為比基尼季節減肥嗎
Are we saving or bodies for bikini season, ladies?
-她好厲害 -最好夠厲害 她收費可高了
- She's good. - She better be. She's expensive.